Finding Aid for Clarence Cook Little Papers 1924-1929
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Papers (Chronological)
  - 1927-1928
    - Murfin, James (Box 9)
      [9-26]
    - Na-Nh (Box 9)
      [9-27]
    - Nelson, J.R. (Box 10)
      [10-1]
    - Newcomb, Howard R. (Box 10)
      [10-2]
    - Ni-Nz (Box 10)
      [10-3]
    - O (Box 10)
      [10-4]
    - Pa-Pe (Box 10)
      [10-5]
    - Patterson, George (Box 10)
      [10-6]
    - Pf-Pq (Box 10)
      [10-7]
    - Pr-Q (Box 10)
      [10-8]
    - Ra-Rg (Box 10)
      [10-9]
    - ROTC (Box 10)
      [10-10]
    - Rh-Rn (Box 10)
      [10-11]
    - Ro-Rz (Box 10)
      [10-12]
    - Rotary (Box 10)
      [10-13]
    - Sa-Sb (Box 10)
      [10-14]
    - Sawyer, Walter H. (Box 10)
      [10-15]
    - Sca-Sch (Box 10)
      [10-16]
    - Sci-Sh (Box 10)
      [10-17]
    - Senate Council (Box 10)
      [10-18]
    - Separate State Universities (Box 10)
      [10-19]
    - Si-Sl (Box 10)
      [10-20]
    - Sm (Box 10)
      [10-21]
    - Smith, Shirley Wheeler (Box 11)
      [11-1]
    - Sn-Ss (Box 11)
      [11-2]
    - St (Box 11)
      [11-3]
    - Stone, Ralph (Box 11)
      [11-4]
    - Student Christian Association (Box 11)
      [11-5]
    - Su-Sz (Box 11)
      [11-6]
    - Ta-Th (Box 11)
      [11-7]
    - Ti-Tt (Box 11)
      [11-8]
    - Treasurer's Report (Box 11)
      [11-9]
    - Tu-Tz (Box 11)
      [11-10]
    - U (Box 11)
      [11-11]
    - University Senate (Box 11)
      [11-12]
    - V (Box 11)
      [11-13]
    - Wa-Wd (Box 11)
      [11-14]
    - Ward, Marcus Llewellyn (Box 11)
      [11-15]
    - Wea-Wez (Box 11)
      [11-16]
    - Wh (Box 11)
      [11-17]
    - Whitney, Allen Sisson (Box 11)
      [11-18]
    - Wia-Wom (Box 11)
      [11-19]
    - Windsor, Russell (Box 11)
      [11-20]
    - Woo-Wz (Box 11)
      [11-21]
    - X-Z (Box 11)
      [11-22]
    - Miscellanea; include Forestry Conference (Box 11)
      [11-23]
    - Miscellanea; include Forestry Conference (Box 11)
      [11-24]
    - Miscellanea; include Forestry Conference (Box 11)
      [11-25]
  - 1928-1929
    - A (Box 12)
      [12-1]
    - Alumni Association (Box 12)
      [12-2]
    - Association of American Colleges (Box 12)
      [12-3]
    - Association of American Universities (Box 12)
      [12-4]
    - Baa-Bq (Box 12)
      [12-5]
    - Board in Control of Athletics (Box 12)
      [12-6]
    - Br-Bz (Box 12)
      [12-7]
    - C (Box 12)
      [12-8]
    - D (Box 12)
      [12-9]
    - Dana, Samuel Trask (Box 12)
      [12-10]
    - Dormitories (Box 12)
      [12-11]
    - E (Box 12)
      [12-12]
    - Edmonson, James Bartlett (Box 12)
      [12-13]
    - F (Box 12)
      [12-14]
    - G (Box 12)
      [12-15]
    - H (Box 12)
      [12-16]
    - I-J (Box 12)
      [12-17]
    - K (Box 12)
      [12-18]
    - L (Box 12)
      [12-19]
    - League of Nations Non-Partisan Association (Box 12)
      [12-20]
    - Ma-Mb (Box 12)
      [12-21]
    - Mc-Mn (Box 12)
      [12-22]
    - Michigan League (Box 12)
      [12-23]
    - Moa-Mz (Box 12)
      [12-24]
    - Na-O (Box 12)
      [12-25]
    - P-Q (Box 12)
      [12-26]
    - R (Box 12)
      [12-27]
    - ROTC (Box 12)
      [12-28]
    - Sa-Sh (Box 12)
      [12-29]
    - Si-Ss (Box 12)
      [12-30]
    - St-Sz (Box 12)
      [12-31]
    - T (Box 12)
      [12-32]
    - Tax Survey (Box 12)
      [12-33]
    - Ten Year Building Program (Box 12)
      [12-34]
    - U (Box 12)
      [12-35]
    - V (Box 12)
      [12-36]
    - W (Box 12)
      [12-37]
    - X-Z (Box 12)
      [12-38]
- Miscellanea
  - 1920-1922-J. Raleigh Nelson Theatre (Box 13)
    [13-1]
  - 1925-1926-Senate Council (Box 13)
    [13-2]
  - 1925-1926-Arts' Development (Box 13)
    [13-3]
  - 1925-1926-Membership File (Box 13)
    [13-4]
  - 1926-Joint Committee of Students and Faculty on Exams, Grades, and Related Subjects (Box 13)
    [13-5]
  - 1926-Honorary degrees conferred in 1926 (Box 13)
    [13-6]
  - 1927-Honorary degrees conferred in 1927 (Box 13)
    [13-7]
  - 1928-Honorary degrees conferred in 1928 (Box 13)
    [13-8]
  - 1929-Honorary degrees conferred in 1929 (Box 13)
    [13-9]
  - 1927-Undergraduate Courses 1927 (Box 13)
    [13-10]
  - 1927-Undergraduate Courses 1927 (Box 13)
    [13-11]
  - 1927-1928-Race Betterment Conference (Box 13)
    [13-12]
  - 1927-1928-Examination Questions (Box 13)
    [13-13]
  - 1928-1929-D.A.R. (Box 13)
    [13-14]
  - undated-Preschool Units (Box 13)
    [13-15]
  - undated-Report of Building Committee of School of Education (Box 13)
    [13-16]
  - 1955, undated (Box 13)
    [13-17]
  - Scrapbook (Box 13)
  - Papers re. Little inauguration (Box 13)
  - Invitations 1925-1929 (Box 14)
- Photographs
  - Portraits of Clarence. C. Little (Box 14)
- Sound Recordings
  - Clarence C. Little, 5 inch reel, 7.5 ips (Box 14)
    The audiotape of President Little was made about 1960, apparently in response to a set of questions submitted by a University of Michigan student. Little discusses specific issues and controversies from his tenure as president and his views on higher education in general. The tape was found in the files of the Campus Broadcasting Network.
Subject Indexes
The subject index is a selective index to subject matter found in the chronologically arranged papers of C.C. Little. Subject entries include name of correspondent or folder, box and folder numbers, and date of document. For alphabet-labelled folders, the name of correspondent is added after the folder number.
Administrative Reorganization and Policy
Admissions policy
Bm-Br (1-28, Bradshaw, 10/29/25)
Na-Nh (3-3, New Trier)
Oa-Oz (3-5, Olmstead, 1/8/26)
Sa-Sq (3-14, Ira Smith, 2/26/26, 3/27/26)
Alumni relations
General:
Wia-Wz (3-27, Wonders, 10/24/25)
Alumni Association (7-2, 5/26/27, responses to alumni survey, 10/14/27, 11/17/27, c.6/21/28, undated report; 7-3, 1/6/28)
Alumni University plan:
Alumni Association (7-2, 5/17/27, 11/29/27, 6/21/28; 7-3, 3/17/28 & passim)
Finances:
Stone (11-4, 9/28/27, 10/13,25,31/27)
Appointment of Publicity Director
Aa-Ai (1-18, Abbot, 4/26/26, 5/13/26)
Bates (1-23, 5/6/26)
Ea-Ez (2-11, Eagan, 8/20/25)
Smith (6-9, 7/9/26)
Athletics Policies
General:
Aa-Az (1-1, Aigler, 4/12/25)
Da-Dz (1-7, E.E. Day, 5/15 & 5/19/25)
Sa-Sz (1-15, Stone, 5/12 & 5/16/25)
Aa-Ai (1-18, Aigler, 4/23/26, 5/6 & 5/14/26)
Bea-Bez (1-24, Bizzell, 6/10/26)
Hubbard (2-27, 4/15 & 4/27/26)
Sundvall (3-19, 4/21/26)
Board in Control of Athletics:
Yost (3-30, 3/16/26)
Board in Control (7-19, 12/26 & 12/27/27; 1/13/28,2/1 & 2/15/28)
Financing of athletics:
S.W.Smith (3-16, 5/10/26; 11-1, 2/18/28)
Board in Control (12-6, 9/22 & 9/25/28, re: financial aid for athletes)
Intercollegiate athletics:
Yost (6-28, 7/21 & 7/25/25, 4-year report of development)
Women's athletics:
Bea-Bez (1-24, Bell, 1/29/26)
Business Office re-organization
Stone (6-12, 2/15/27, 5/28/27)
Dean of Women, Office of
Hamilton (2-20, passim)
Murfin (3-2, 5/6,11,14,17/26)
Ni-Nz (3-4, Nites, 6/18/26)
Ra-Rn (3-8, Richards, 4/27/26)
Women's League (3-28, 12/4/25 & undated notes)
S.W.Smith (6-9, 7/14 & 7/28/26)
Freshman orientation
Caa-Caz (1-31, Carver, 2/18/26)
Sa-Sq (3-14, I.M.Smith, 5/26/26)
I.M.Smith (6-10, 5/2/27)
Bursley (7-23, 9/27/27)
Housing for women
Effinger (2-12, 1/23/26)
Sawyer (6-6, 12/23/26)
S.W.Smith (11-1, 10/6/27, 11/2,7,8/27, 12/13/27)
See also: Dormitories under Sec. III. Building Program
Registrar's Office reorganized
Ea-Ez (1-8, Effinger, 5/12 & 5/13/25)
Sa-Sz (1-15, S.W.Smith, 4/27/25, 6/3/25)
M.E.Cooley (2-7, 12/2/25)
Ra-Rn (3-8, Rich, 3/5/26)
Si-Sq (3-14, I.M.Smith, 8/10/25, 4/23/26)
Retirement policies and benefits
S.W.Smith (3-15, 1/4/26; 3-16, 4/3/26; 11-1, 2/29/28, 4/5/28)
C (12-8, Carnegie Corp., 9/24/28, 5/1/29; Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement Teaching, 12/3/28, (4/2/29)
Riggs Fellowships
Ra-Rz (1-14, Riggs, Apr. & June 1925)
Lloyd (2-36, 1/18/26)
Riggs (5-26, 1926-27, entire)
Stone (6-12, 1/14,17,26/27, 4/14,15,16,19,21,25/27, 5/12 & 5/19/27)
R (12-17, Riggs, 9/13/28 to 5/7/29)
State relations
Green (8-31, 6/23/28)
Separate State Universities (10-19, entire)
Si-Sl (10-20, Sink, 6/8/28)
S.W.Smith (11-1, 12/28/27)
Tax Survey (12-33, 10/3/28 ff.)
Student discipline
Alcohol use:
Ea-Ez (1-8, Everitt, 6/22/25)
Ra-Rz (1-14, Rumney, 5/15/25 re: use of liquor at alumni meetings)
Da-De (2-9, Delphey, 1/2/26)
Haa-Haz (2-19, Harper, 11/10/25)
Hamilton (2-20, 5/25 & 5/28/26)
Laa-Laz (2-34, Literary Digest, 4/28/26)
Na-Nh (3-3, N.Y.Sun, 4/27/26)
Waa-Waz (3-24, Watson, 4/15/29)
S.W.Smith (6-9, 2/18/27)
Bursley (7-23, 5/24/28)
Automobile use on campus:
S.W.Smith (3-15, 11/18/25)
Bursley (4-11, 7/22/26, 8/31/26, 4/22/27; 7-23, 1/6/28, 3/9/28
Murfin (5-17, 7/22/26)
Green (8-31, 9/26/27, 11/21/27)
University College
General:
Caa-Caz (1-31, Campbell, 4/2/26)
Hoa-Hoz (2-24, Hopkins, 3/19/26)
J (James, 2/1 & 2/10/26)
M.E.Cooley (4-19, 5/20/27)
Hubbard (9-9, 4/11/28, 5/2/28)
Patterson (10-6, 3/3 & 3/5/28)
Whitney (11-18, 11/22/27, 3/5/28)
G (12-15, Grant, 4/18/29)
Committee appointments:
Committee on appointments (8-4, 11/10/27, 12/22/27, 6/9,ll,12,13,15/28)
Efforts in other states:
Miscellanea, 1927 (13-11, 2/3,8,9,23/27;Feb. 1927, Wisconsin Experimental College)
Reactions to plan:
Fa-Fh (2-13, Ferris, 3/3/26)
Alumni Association (7-3, 4/28/28)
Clements (8-2, 3/22/28)
Dean of Engineering (8-12, 12/2/27)
Sawyer (10-15, 3/19/28, re: LSA action on proposal)
Miscellanea, 1927 (13-11, Undergraduate courses II, 5/11 & 5/17/27, c.6/21/27 re: opposition of Engineering faculty)
Undergraduate courses:
Miscellanea, 1927 (13-10, Undergraduate courses I, undated, c.Mar.1927, 3/7/27, 4/4,5,8/27, 5/6/27)
Miscellanea, 1927 (13-11, Undergraduate courses II, 2/2,17,21/27, Summaries of course content and various undated reports and proposals)
See also University of Michigan. University College. Records.
General
II. Building Program
Ci-Cz (1-6, Committee of Five, Minutes, 5/29/25)
Sa-Sz (1-15, Shepard, 6/6/25; S.W.Smith, 4/23/25)
Dean's Conference (8-11, 11/8/27 re: re-use of old museum building)
S.W.Smith (11-1, 2/20/28, 6/1/28)
Building needs
Ten Year Building Program (12-34, 10/1,5,6,8,11/28 re: Business School, Art Museum, Power House, Libraries, Medical, Law, Engineering & Education Schools; 11/6/28 re: financing)
Burton Memorial Tower
Bi-Bl (1-26, Bibbins, 11/19/25)
Dormitories
Aj-Az (1-19, Angell, 4/20/26)
Hamilton (2-20, 4/10/26)
Alumni Association (7-3, 3/30/28, 6/23/28)
Dormitories (8-16, 5/15/21, 3/30/28 re: governance of women's dormitories, 3/1/28 re: financing; 12-11, passim, reports on public hearing and reactions to proposal)
S.W. Smith (11-1, 3/5/28 re: housing for nurses)
Stone (11-4, 10/24/27, 2/7 & 2/10/28, 5/8/28)
Alumni Association (12-2, 1/4/29 re: financing)
Student Christian Association (12-31, 1/10/29 re: proposed dormitory for international students)
Law School
General:
Bates (1-23, 10/10/25, 2/18/26, 5/14/26; 4-6, 7/12/26, 8/17/26, 2/17/27)
Cook (4-18, 2/24/27, 4/7,9,30/27)
Library:
Sawyer (3-13, 1/22/26, 2/8/26)
Bates (4-6, 4/15 & 4/23/27, 6/27/27; 7-13, undated, c.Aug. 1927, 10/28/27)
Lorch Hall (Architecture)
Beal (1-25, 3/26/26)
Ce-Ch (2-1, Christensen, 4/1/26)
Clements (2-3, 10/15/25, 4/14/26)
Palmer Field and Clubhouse (women's physical education)
S.W. Smith (6-9, 9/20/26)
Board in Control of Athletics (7-19, 5/26/28, 6/13/28)
Ruthven Museum
S.W.Smith (6-9, 3/17 & 3/24/27, 6/3/27)
School of Education
Whitney (3-26, 3/13/26; 11-18, 10/15/27, 1/23/28)
Clements (8-2, 5/9/28)
Edmonson (12-13, 9/26/28, 10/1 & 10/10/28, 11/28/28, 12/21/28)
Miscellanea, Pre-school units (13-15, 3/26 & 3/28/28, 4/30/28, 6/12/28, 7/16/28, 10/12/28)
Miscellanea, Building Committee of School of Education (13-16, entire)
Stadium
General:
Baa-Bh (1-3, Bates, 4/10/25, Senate Council opposition to larger than 50,000 capacity stadium)
Aa-Ai (1-18, Aigler, 3/13 & 3/19/26)
Di-Dz (2-10, Duffy, 6/10/26)
Haa-Haz (2-19, Hadden, 1/25 & 1/30/26)
J (2-30, Johnston, 3/1/26, 4/3/26)
Sa-Sh (3-12, Shaw, 3/4/26)
Wia-Wz (3-27, Wilbur, 3/22/26)
Yost (6-28, 7/6/26, 4/9/27)
Construction:
St-Sz (3-17, Stone & Webster, 5/19/26)
Ta-Tz (3-20, Turner Construction, 1/28/26)
Waa-Waz (3-24, Ward, 12/3/25, dissatisfaction with delays)
Yost (3-30, 11/3/25, editorial on delays)
Dedication:
Board in Control of Athletics (7-19, 9/13/27 & passim)
Dedication Game, October 22, 1927 (8-14, entire)
Plans:
Maa-O (1-12, Murfin, 3/28/25)
Sa-Sz (1-15, Stone, 5/23/25)
Reports:
Yost (3-30, undated "report on ticket problem")
Yost (6-28, undated "report on stadium")
Women's League
General:
Bi-Bl (1-26, Blodgett, 5/19/26)
Ce-Ch (2-1, Christensen, 3/10/26)
Hamilton (2-20, 2/15/25)
V (3-23, Vandenberg, 12/17/25)
Michigan League II (5-15, 1/28/26, 2/9/26, 2/18/26 re: appointment of Mrs. Henderson to replace Dean Hamilton)
Financing:
Michigan League I (5-14, 6/11/26, Aug. 1926, 9/16/26, 10/27/26, 1/29/27, 4/22/27)
Michigan League II (5-15, 1/28 & 1/30/26, 2/14/26, 4/7/26, 6/4 & 6/18/26, 5/19/27)
Michigan League-Alumni Council (9-23, 6/18/27, summary report, 2/24/28, 3/12/28)
Ground-breaking:
Michigan League I (5-14, 6/10/27)
Murfin, (5-17, 6/11/27)
S.W.Smith (6-9, 5/24/27, 6/1/27)
Operation and use:
Michigan League-Alumni Council (9-23, 6/19/28, letter and undated proposal; 6/29/28)
Murfin (9-26, 6/25/28)
Michigan League (12-23, entire, re: governance)
III. Academic units: Changes and additions
Anthropology
Executive Committee Matters (8-22, 4/28/28 re: adding Department of Anthropology)
Arts, Instruction and research in
Effinger (2-12, 12/29/25, 1/15/26, 5/12/26, re: theater)
Miscellanea, 1925-1926-Arts Development (13-3, 7/28/26 re: need for museum)
Biological Station, Douglas Lake
St-Sz (3-17, Strong, 4/21/26)
Biology & Engineering Camps (7-17, passim)
Clements Library
Bi-Bl (1-26, Blakeslee, 1/14/26 re: acquisition of Nathaniel Greene papers)
4-16 (Clements Library, 12/29/16)
See also: Randolph G. Adams correspondence in alphabet-labelled folders
Dental School
Ward (6-21, 12/21/26 re: changing to School of Dentistry; 3/30/27, 4/11/27 re: curriculum in first two years)
Dutch studies
Haa-J (1-10, Mrs. Hulst, 3/7/25 re: offer of Dutch community in Michigan to establish Dutch studies at U-M)
Bm-Br (1-28, Bok, 1/21/26)
Education, School of
General:
Ci-Cz (1-6, Cody, 4/27/25, report on need for expansion of Ed. School curriculum)
Effinger (2-12, 12/28/25, 4/21 & 4/28/26; 4-24, 5/5 & 5/24/27)
Hoa-Hz (5-5, Huckle, 2/14/27)
La-Li (5-9, Life, 6/13/27)
Whitney (3-26, 6/9/26; 6-23, 2/11/17 re: establishing Dept. of Mental Hygiene)
Edmonson (12-13, 7/26/28 re: compensation for outside work)
Elementary laboratory school:
Whitney (11-18, 6/15/27, 12/15/27)
Practice teaching:
Edmonson (12-13, 8/1/28)
Pre-school plans:
Miscellanea - Pre-school units (13-15, 11/18/27 & passim)
Relations with LSA:
Certification of teachers by LSA:
Waa-Z (1-17, Whitney, 4/20/25)
Whitney (11-18, 5/16/27, 10/29/27, 11/17/27)
Separate functions of LSA & School of Ed.:
Whitney, (6-23, 5/2 & 5/9/27)
Relation to University College:
Whitney (11-18, 11/22/27, 12/15/27, 1/9/28)
Teaching loads:
Whitney (6-23, 4/15/25)
Engineering and Architecture, School of
Geodesy & Surveying, Department of:
Biology and Engineering Camps (7-17, 12/17/27, 4/19/28 re: removal of Camp Davis to Wyoming)
Engineering education:
Bi-Bz (1-26, Blanchard, 4/29 & 4/30/26 re: establishment of Dept. of Traffic Engineering & Highway Transport)
Na-Nh (3-3, Nelson, 5/22/26, 6/2/26)
Murfin (5-17, 4/19/27 re: outside work)
Hubbard (9-9, 5/2,9,10/28 re: establishing separate College of Architecture)
Nelson (10-1, entire)
Patterson (10-6, 2/12 & 2/14/28 re: English teaching in Engineering School)
Research:
Ra-Rz (1-14, Riggs, Mar.-May 1925, reports of State Highway Laboratory; also in Ra-Rn (3-8, Riggs)
Ce-Ch (2-1, Chapin, 11/14/25 re: transportation research)
Cooley, M.E. (2-7, 10/16/25, 11/19/25; 4-19, 7/22/26, 8/10/26, 9/15 & 9/30/26, 10/8/26, 11/4,5,11/26 re: Aeronautical engineering research)
Hanchett (2-21, 5/13/26 re: synthetic rubber)
Smith, S.W. (6-9, 12/21/26, 2/28/27 re: patent control; 11-1, 4/5/28)
Stone (11-4, 2/3/28)
See also A.E.White correspondence in alphabet-labelled folders after box 4
Transportation Library, Establishment of:
Ce-Ch (2-1, Church, 5/10/26; Chapin, 3/26/26, 4/19/26
Ra-Rn (3-8, Ripley, 4/10/26; Riggs, 5/8,13,17/26)
Extension Service
Cooley, M.E. (2-7, 12/8/25, proposal for advanced courses in Applied Mechanics)
Hea-Hi (5-3, Henderson, 2/3/27)
Fellowship in Creative Arts
F-G (1-9, Frost, 4/21 & 4/23/25, 6/1 & 6/25/25)
Bm-Br (1-28, Brandt, 8/11/25)
Effinger (2-12, 4/13/26)
St-Sz (3-17, Stephenson, 7/30/25)
Wia-Wz (3-27, Williams, 6/30/25 - 5/29/26)
C (12-8, Creative Arts Fellowship, 8/1/28)
Forestry and Conservation, School of
General:
Ea-Ez (1-8, Effinger, 6/27/25 re: attempts to find suitable head)
Sa-Sz (1-15, S.W.Smith, c.4/27/25; Stinchfield, 3/31/25)
Beal (1-25, 3/19/26)
Dana (8-9, 11/2/27; 12-10, 7/7/28 re: acquisition of site for experiment station, 4/15/27 re: expansion of department into School of Forestry & Conservation)
Forestry conferences:
Miscellanea; include Forestry Conference (11-23, 1/25/27 re: Chicago meeting on forest conservation)
Miscellanea; include Forestry Conference (11-24, passim; 11-25, 4/5/27, 5/2/27 ff. re: Ann Arbor meeting on conservation & teaching of forestry at U-M)
Forestry research:
Dana (8-9, 12/5,13,19/27, 3/29/28, 5/29/28 re: Institute of Forest Research; 12-10, 5/17/29)
Law School
General:
Bua-Buz (1-29, Busby, 2/17/26 re: faculty organization)
Effinger (2-12, 2/18/26)
Murfin (9-26, 6/7 & 6/25/28 re: adding American Institute)
Administration of Lawyers' Club:
Bates (1-23, 10/8 & 10/21/25, 1/27/26, 2/27/26; 4-6, 8/9/26)
Coo-Coz (2-6, Cook, 7/8,10,16/25, 12/3 & 12/9/25)
Lawyers' Club Minutes (2-35, Nov.,1925 - Apr.1926; 9-17, 8/20/27, 2/3/28, 3/10 & 3/20/28 re: management)
Sawyer (3-13, 6/1 & 6/30/25, 7/1 & 7/3/25)
Cook (4-18, 8/19/26 re: finances; 9/8/26 re: representation on Board of Governors)
La-Li (5-9, Lawyers' Club, 8/2/26, 12/18 & 12/29/26, 1/12,20,29/27, 2/9 & 2/21/28ff.)
R (12-27, Regents, 1/8/29 re: planning financing)
Legal research, Establishing Institute for:
Bates (1-23, 12/14 & 12/26/25, 5/25/26, 6/10/26; 4-6, 8/17 & 8/31/26, 12/14/26)
Coo-Coz (2-6, Creighton, 3/18/26)
Cook (4-18, 9/20 & 27/26, 10/12/26, 11/5,16,26/26, 1/8/27, 3/8/27)
Literature, Science, and the Arts, College of
Anthropology, Department of, added:
Executive Committee Matters (8-22, 4/28/28)
Combining English, Rhetoric & Public Speaking in one department:
Caa-Caz (1-31, Campbell, 11/23/26)
Coo-Coz (2-6, Cowden, 5/24/26)
Effinger (2-12, 5/26/26, 6/10/26; 4-24, 1/13 & 1/17/27)
I (2-28, Immel, 1/19/26)
Jack (9-14, 12/23/27, 1/16/28)
Curriculum:
Effinger (4-24, 11/17/26, 12/10/26)
Greenland Expedition, 1926-27:
Hobbs Expedition (2-25, entire)
Hoa-Hz (5-5, Hobbs, 9/18 & 9/23/26)
Library Science course (new):
Bishop (1-27, 5/6 & 5/17/26 re: faculty hiring)
Fm-Fz (2-15, Frankhauser, 2/10/26)
S.W.Smith (3-16, 4/28/26)
Medical School and Hospital
General:
Cabot (1-32, 10/19/25, 1/15 & 1/19/26, 3/16/26, 4/12/26 re: curriculum)
Gore (8-30, 10/28/27, 11/3/27 re: admissions)
Homeopathic Department:
Baa-Bh (1-3, Beebe, 6/8/25 re: budget reduction for Homeopathic Department)
Si-Sq (3-14, Springer, Oct. 1925 re: completion of merger with Medical School)
Outside work (clinical work vs. teaching):
Haynes (2-22, 6/16/26; 5-2, 7/12/26, 11/12/26ff.)
Cabot (1-23, c.11/16/25, 2/19/26; 4-13, 11/2/26, 5/23/27 re: salaries; 7-25, 4/5/28; 12-8, 1/2/29; re: salaries)
Sawyer (6-6, 12/13/26)
S.W.Smith (6-9, 2/15/27)
Tuberculosis patients, Care of:
Stone (6-12, 10/15/26)
Women in Medical School:
Cabot (4-13, undated c.Nov. 1926, 2/7/27)
Haynes (5-2, 3/30/26 re: nurses' training)
Student Health Service
Hanchett (12-16, 8/7 & 8/17/28)
IV. Student life and social problems on campus
Housing
Dormitories (8-16, 2/11/28, clippings from Michigan Daily; undated, statement of landladies re: plans for dorms. See also Nellie Felker correspondence in alphabet-labelled folders.)
Race relations
General:
Na-Nh (3-3, Negro-Caucasian Club, Mar. 1926)
Bates (4-6, 12/23/26)
Housing for black students:
Baa-Bh (1-3, O.W.Baker, 4/23 & 4/30/25)
Fa-G (1-9, Franklin, 5/9 & 5/27/25, 6/27/25, 7/7/25)
Haa-J (1-10, Haynes, 6/24/25)
Aa-Ai (7-1, Advisers to Women, Oct.1927-May 1928)
Radicalism
Ra-Rn (3-8, Reynolds, 5/25/26)
Religion
Observances:
Fa-G (1-9, Rabbi Franklin, 4/13/25 re: observance of Jewish High Holy Days)
St-Sz (3-17, 4/2/26 re: Sunday convocations)
Student Christian Association:
Coa-Con (2-5, Coffman, 11/25/25, 1/9/26)
S.W.Smith(3-16, 3/3/26)
St-Sz (3-17, Student Christian Association, 6/29/26)
Hoa-Hz (5-5, Hobbs, 1/27,29,31/29, 2/9/27 re: speaker on pacifism)
Student Christian Association (6-14, entire, includes financial reports; 11-5, 2/28/28, 3/13/28, both re: proposed International House; passim, disposition of buildings owned)
Women students
Aa-Ai (7-1 Advisers to Women, passim re: housing for women) See also Section I. Housing for women and Section II. Dormitories)
Women's League minutes (3-28, passim re: Student Council representation)
V. Educational issues of local/national importance
Academic freedom
Aa-Az (1-1, AAUP, 3/17/25 re: reply to New Republic editorial outlining measures to prevent abuses)
Consolidation of education institutions in state
Governor's Committee (4-31, entire)
Engineering education, Philosophy of
Ci-Cz (1-6, M.E.Cooley, 4/25/25)
M.E. Cooley (2-7, 3/3,4,24/26, 4/6/26, 5/19/26; 4-19, 8/31/26, re: need for broad background in faculty, 9/14/26, 10/5/26)
Social hygiene education
American Social Hygiene Association (7-9, entire)
Status of women in universities
Henderson (5-3, 1/31/27)
VI. Social and political issues of the time
Eugenics and Birth Control
Aj-Az (1-19, American Birth Control League, 11/24/25)
American Association for Medical Progress (1-20, 3/16/26, 5/8,11,13/26)
Clements (2-3, 12/7/25)
Ea-Ez (2-11, Eugenics Committee, 4/20/25, 9/29/25, 11/21 & 11/24/25, 12/22/25)
Moa-Mz (3-1, Mulford, 4/20/26; Morris, 1/30/26, 4/6/26)
St-Sz (3-17, Stoneman, 5/24/26)
Ta-Tz (3-20, Turner, 3/24 & 3/26/26)
Waa-Waz (3-24, Walker, 11/5/25 re: sterilization of the "unfit")
Wb-Wh (3-25, Whitney, 12/7/25)
X,Y,Z (3-29, Zahn, 11/24/25; Yarros, 3/1/26)
American Birth Control League (4-2, news clippings on Little's advocacy of birth control and related correspondence; 7-6, entire)
Hoa-Hz (5-5, Hunt, 6/1/27)
World Population Conference (6-26, entire)
American Eugenics Society (7-8, entire)
Miscellanea, 1927-1928 (13-12, Race Betterment Conference, entire)
Freedom of speech
Miscellanea, 1928-1929 (13-14, D.A.R. entire re: controversy over Little's criticism of D.A.R. "blacklist" of liberals, pacifists & un-Americans)
Immigration, Exclusion acts
H-J (1-10, Japan Times & Mail, 3/18/25, letter of Alfred H. Lloyd re: Immigration Act)
Laa-Lz (2-34, Lum, 1/8/26)
Jack, P.M. (9-14, Oct.1927-May 1928, passim re: changing bill to admit professors)
Low cost housing
Housing Association (9-7, entire)
Prohibition
Ce-Ch (2-1, Christian Science Monitor, 12/14/15)
Ea-Ez (2-11, Ever-Ready Can Co, 6/2/26)
J (2-30, H.B. Joy, 5/27/26)
Me-Mi (2-39, Michener, 5/27/26)
World Peace
Me-Mi (2-39, Michigan Council for World Peace, 12/23/25)
League of Nations Non-Partisan Association (12-20, entire)